Ryan Skeans

(951) 234-1872 | ryanskeans@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in Typescript, CSS, Web Components, and React. Proven success in spearheading feature development and collaborating with stakeholders to deliver clients' needs on time. Experienced in agile methodologies, code refactoring, bug fixing, and code development.

Experience

SS&C Advent | San Francisco, CA Software Engineer | 02/2022 - Present

- Integrated both REST and GraphQL API's into our investment management application to enable seamless tracking and rebalancing of client assets.
- Implemented a trading program using React and Redux that allowed users to quickly harvest short and long term losses across their portfolios.
- Wrote tests and collaborated with QA/QE teams to ensure a high quality user experience at all times.
- Utilized a JavaScript data visualization framework to craft dynamic SVG charts, enabling clients to easily identify key areas within their investments.
- Collaborated closely with backend developers to implement data-rich grids that effectively conveyed vital portfolio and individual security information.
- Contributed to the company-wide design system built using native Web Components, which allowed components to be used with any frontend framework.
- · Leveraged tools like Jenkins, Github Actions, and Docker images to get work done efficiently and quickly.

Prudential Financial | San Francisco, CA Senior Product Management Associate | 07/2020 - 02/2022

- Worked to build and enhance Prudential's retail/direct to consumer money management products.
- Analyzed and provided insights on client engagement data using Tableau and Adobe Analytics.
- Participated in design sprints aimed at rapidly prototyping and integrating user feedback as early as possible in the design process.
- Helped unblock and guide user stories to completion in an agile workplace.

Prudential Financial | Sunnyvale, CA Product Management Intern | 06/2019 - 08/2019

- Worked collaboratively with UX, UI, and backend engineers to develop intuitive workflows based on competitive research.
- Helped review, summarize, and distribute results from multiple rounds of user testing for our product.
- Created low fidelity wire frames and coordinated with UX teams to refine based on industry best practices.

Top Skills

React, Web Components, Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, REST API's, GraphQL, Cypress, Web Services, SQL, Node.js, Express.js, Webpack, Material, D3.js, Git, GitHub, NPM, Python

Education

California Polytechnic State University | San Luis Obispo, CA B.S. Business Administration, Financial Management | 06/2020

Websites

Github: https://github.com/skeanster

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanskeans/

Personal Website: https://skeanster.github.io/